with the market right here need now icsl
Lombard that's the company in Focus
they've posted a recovery in their
premium collections let's try and
understand what really is the Outlook
going forward and what's happening with
the company we've got on board with us
bhavas Gupta the MD and CEO at ICS Aloma
General Insurance joining in parav hi
good morning great to have you on the
show thanks for joining ET now uh you
know I'm just going through your
earnings there's been a recovery on a
month and- Monon basis as well and you
know by the monthly data July witnessed
an uptick in premium collection
do you see the trend actually hold up
barav and has August also translated
well in terms of Premium
collections uh first thank you for
having me on your show and uh good
morning to all your viewers uh so yeah
what we've seen is uh if you see
month-on-month numbers April May June
July we are seeing uh a decent
Improvement uh across months uh April of
course was really slow may you know was
early times of pickup uh but June was a
positive month for the industry and for
us July was even more so uh looking
ahead uh the trend line gives us some
amount of comfort uh having said that
there is one bit of worry that remains
that U uh the the the these the sporadic
changes that is happening in terms of
lockdowns in certain cities at different
points in time uh that is a cause of
concern so our senses it will be
strongly correlated to what we see with
the virus and uh if we finally see some
tapering coming through in the next few
weeks or thereafter then we should see a
good festive season for us the motor you
know insurance is a large piece so if we
see some some stabilization of this uh
pandemic then we'll see a good uh
festive season on the other side that
was on the on the motor side on the
health there is generally a uh you know
consistent Improvement that we are
seeing uh there is some amount of uh
kind of flattening of the demand uh
increase that we were seeing uh the
demand is still elevated but we are not
seeing the increase in the rate of uh
you know growth that we were seeing
earlier and that's also probably
understandable because there's some
amount of saturation of of the numbers
that we are seeing at the health side
but overall yes the trend looks
positive Mr Das Gupta nikunj Dal also
joining in good to have you and good to
connect with you it's been a while we've
spoken on air my my big picture question
is the insurance industry the segment
which you represent General insurance
industry has seen a kager growth of
about 14 15% in last 10 years because of
this pandemic crisis could there any
could there be a structural change
there good connecting with you n yeah
and and as I said Thank you for having
me on your show um look uh in terms of
the overall trend line that we see with
the medium to long term you know of
course this year is a discontinuity for
every industry and for us it's a
discontinuity
uh and the growth numbers you know
obviously will not be in line with what
we've seen in the past having said that
I think General Insurance business will
still show a you know some amount of
growth uh even if it's a single digit
growth for the year we will have a
growth which itself is quite remarkable
in the current context but if I come
back to your question on the more
structural changes we genely believe
that there is a huge Runway of growth
for this industry there is a under
penetration at a level which is uh uh
which even if you compare with let's say
bricks Nations uh if you let's say
compare with China our insurance density
is almost 110th Chinese numbers I'm not
even comparing with the Western World so
there is a huge Runway of growth and our
sense is that uh this industry will
continue to grow at least two and a half
times real GDP growth for the
foreseeable
future okay you have a formidable track
record that data which is out there in
the public public domain that a pad
growth of more than 20% much better than
the industry but because of this
acquisition will your historical growth
numbers get challenged because in BH
acquisition well it's going to be
dilutive you're taking some crop
insurance there their Opex is very high
so obviously this will be pushing you
back look uh coming to that deal uh you
know there are many factors that we've
looked at when we've uh you know
considered the uh you know the scheme U
that we just announced over the weekend
um in terms of our numbers uh obviously
I can't give you any uh forward looking
statement but if you look at our 10 12
year history and even in a period where
because of deification the prices
dropped tremendously in this period from
2008 onwards we've had more more than
20% caser in terms of profit after tax
over this 12 year cycle so there are
certain things that we've kind of
focused on in terms of being disciplined
in terms of being a building a
sustainable business and that philosophy
doesn't change now when when we look at
the uh the the potential merger of
course it's subject to all regulatory
approvals uh there are uh huge amount of
synergies that we see in the two
businesses uh we see uh very uh high
level cultural fit and a good talent
base you know in the in in B EXA which
in our mind is a very important factor
that at times doesn't get uh considered
in the numbers when you look at
integration uh and overall high quality
uh governance uh uh you know and and a
reputation of the of the partners you
know the investors so all of these
factors went into play when we looked at
this transaction now if you look at the
synergies there is of course Revenue
Synergy in terms of the distribution
Outreach that we get in terms of cost
Synergy if you look at uh you know BH AA
there are slightly smaller in size right
and there is a certain scale uh
disadvantages that you have at at that
size and if you look at their operating
cost the expense ratio as we call it uh
that's about 42% while for us it is in
the 20s you know maybe 26 27% depending
on which you look at so there is a huge
amount of cost Synergy that we believe
we will see on top of the revenue
Synergy that I talked
about that you will now get back into
crop insurance something consciously
which you have avoided isn't that going
to be in
baggage look our view on crop insurance
was always driven by the current
reinsurance terms and the pricing in the
market fundamentally and philosophically
we like the crop insurance business
because the way the scheme was designed
we always believed it was probably the
best architectured scheme that we've
seen over the last you know at least 20
years that we've been in business and
we've been doing crop insurance from
2009 onwards uh so you know and and
these discontinuities also can change
some of those Dynamics and if let's say
the underwriting model you rather the
you know the pricing in the market
changes which we are beginning to see
some improvement and if the reinsurance
uh you know Market changes then it could
become a viable business again for us uh
it was as I said a call taken given the
current reality of the crop insurance at
that point in time now in this situation
you know BH Exel has some commitments
threeyear commitments in terms of uh
crop insurance that they've written we
will obviously honored that thereafter
we will study you know in terms of the
uh the uh quality of business and the
market dynamics at that point in time
and if we believe that it makes sense
for uh both our policyholder and our
shareholders to continue we will
continue just when your CD ratio was
nearing 100% And you were about to take
a gantly forward will the pandemic push
all those ratios down I mean can we
assume that whatever plans you had for
fy21 because of Corona everything will
be implemented but it's like everything
is got delayed by three to four quarters
is my broad assessment right on other
ratios like combined ratio I mean CD
ratio and other things look I can't give
you a forward-looking statement on
combined ratio but just to give you a
sense that where we are and what we've
been driving our Focus has been in terms
of as I said disciplined underwriting so
that the combin ratio stays around 100
and ultimately deliver a 20% R and
that's something you've seen us being a
to deliver since the time we've been
listed uh going ahead that objective
doesn't change and we remain reasonably
confident in the medium term to be able
to continue to deliver that uh
performance sure parav I know you've got
a run at 950 but just an extension to
the point that you were making right now
you've managed to maintain your market
share at 8 and 1 half% x crop uh with
the merger now you're going to be the
third largest player which are the
segments you think are going to be the
key growth drivers for you both in terms
of revenues as well as market share
going
forward so if you look at the segmental
market share you know post this mergin
on a performa basis uh one uh you know
key segment that we've been uh focused
on and even bti XA has been very strong
in is motor and our overall market share
moves from 10% to 12% on a performa
basis now even uh with a 12% Market it
is not as if you know there is no head
room for growth we continue to believe
that motor will continue to do well
obviously this this year has been a a
bit of a setback on the motor side but
in the medium to long term we believe
that segment will continue to grow the
second segment that we've been always uh
talking a lot about is the uh is the
health and there we are particularly for
new health business we are seeing rapid
growth and in the distribution franchise
that we are uh you know hoping to uh
bring in because of the V acquisition we
believe there's an opportunity to cross
sell and upsell some of our Health
products and the new health you know
initiative that we are launching lastly
our Focus remains onme corporate and the
digital piece those two will continue
and even there uh part EXA has built
some initial building blocks in terms of
scaling those businesses up which will
be complimentary to us
okay B great to have you on the show and
we should chat more often here on ET now